The return of the great adventure.
Raiders of the Lost Ark is a adventure, action
film directed by Steven Spielberg.
Indiana Jones – the tweed-suited professor who just happens to be a celebrated archaeologist – is hired by the
government to locate the legendary Ark of the Covenant, he finds himself up against the entire Nazi regime.
Indiana Jones, played by Harrison Ford.
Marion Ravenwood, played by Karen Allen.
Dr. René Belloq, played by Paul Freeman.
Sallah, played by John Rhys-Davies.
Major Arnold Toht, played by Ronald Lacey.
Colonel Dietrich, played by Wolf Kahler.
Raiders of the Lost Ark: Original Motion Picture Soundtrack is the film score
to the 1981 Steven Spielberg film, Raiders of the Lost Ark.
The music was composed and conducted by John Williams and
performed by the London Symphony Orchestra.
The orchestrations were provided by Herbert W.
Spencer and Al Woodbury.
The score was released by Columbia Records in June 1981.
The soundtrack received an Academy Award nomination for Best Original
Score but lost out to Vangelis' score for Chariots of Fire.
This was one of the first scores recorded at Abbey Road Studios (formerly
known as EMI Studios) after Anvil Studios shut down in 1980.
The film explores themes of egypt, treasure,
medallion, swastika, saving the world.